CHRISTINA BAILEY

Denton, TX 76209 | 9402318200 | shaymbailey@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Organized and dependable IT Specialist proficient at task management and prioritization. Savvy expert experienced in troubleshooting computer hardware and software issues in customer-focused environments. Possesses comprehensive knowledge of standard operating systems, networking protocols and technical support procedures. Skilled in identifying and resolving complex technical problems.

SKILLS

- Flexible and Adaptable, Data Entry, Customer Service
- Web Developer: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, DOM, APIs, jQuery
- OS, Microsoft platform, G-Suite
- System administration: Maintenance and Repair
- Programming: SQL, Java, Python, C#, JSON, PHP

- Active Listening, Decision-Making, Problem-Solving, Critical Thinking, Training Program Improvement,
- Written Communication,
 Interpersonal Communication,
 Technical Writing
- Organization and Time Management
- Teamwork, Collaboration, Team building, Self-Motivated

WORK HISTORY

SEPTEMBER 2020-CURRENT

Technical Escalations Engineer | Turnitin, Llc | Denton, TX

- Responsible for managing escalations relating to products or services, handling advanced troubleshooting tickets, and providing feedback to upper management regarding customer issues
- Other responsibilities include assisting with training, providing resources and learning opportunities to Level one support to become Subject matter experts.
- Assisted customers in identifying issues and explained solutions to restore service and functionality.
- Translated complex technical issues into digestible language for non-technical users.
- Used ticketing systems to manage and process support actions and requests.

- Provided Tier 1 IT support to non-technical internal users through desk side support services.
- Identified potential sales and cross-selling opportunities in course of delivery of support services.
- Contributed to reductions in employee turnover by revamping training programs
- Exceeded goals through effective task prioritization and great work ethic

AUGUST 2019-APRIL 2020

Project Coordinator | TRCA

- Responsible for planning, scheduling and monitoring project roll outs and implementations independently or as part of team, as well as serving as central point of contact for project team to ensure successful objective completion
- Providing customer service and working with other departments.
- Coordinated presentations for customers and project members to detail project scope, progress and results
- Prepared meeting agendas and minutes for distribution and record keeping
- Maintained database and spreadsheets with accurate inventory and status
- Assisted with onboarding newly hired staff members
- Managed competing demands and professionally adapted to frequent change

SEPTEMBER 2018-JULY 2019

Technical Support | InTech Together

- Provided Level 1 support to customers via phone, virtual online meetings, and online support ticket system
- Healthcare IT support plan inside and out
- Basic knowledge of Operating Systems, Software Drivers, Middleware, I/O Devices, and computer hardware
- Knowledge of enterprise software and/or CRM
- Understanding of LAN Networks and Remote Desktop Access.

MAY 2018-SEPTEMBER 2018

Customer Service Representative | Pestroutes

- Answer inbound calls and greet customers
- Manage credit card processing when necessary
- Adhere to quality standards determined by company and client
- Represent company in professional and ethical manner
- Maintain high level of customer satisfaction with focus on first call resolution
- Resolve customer requests by investigating problems, developing solutions and recommend additional products and/or services relevant to assessment of customer needs.

NOVEMBER 2015-JUNE 2017

Help Desk Analyst | CareView Communications, Inc.

- Provide support for user problems relating to hardware, software and telephone issues
- Train all new hires
- Follow-up on unresolved issues and projects, test fixes to ensure problems have been resolved
- Assist with internal physical moves of PCs, telephone,
- Help in setup of on line training courses,
- Escalate issues to as appropriate to higher level specialists
- Manage user accounts, software updates and password resets
- Manage severs through MySQL database

SEPTEMBER 2014-SEPTEMBER 2015

IT Specialist | CompuCom

- Working closely with either end users or customers in IT related issues,
- Configured hardware, devices and software to set up work stations for employees.
- Suggested software and hardware modifications to reduce lag time and improve overall speed.
- Removed malware, ransomware and other threats from laptops and desktop systems.
- Rolled out software updates and applied server patches to thwart threats from penetrating networks.
- Explained technical information in clear terms to promote better understanding for non-technical users.
- Worked with software development team on reported errors and bugs and assisted in deployment of release fixes.
- Collaborated with vendors to locate replacement components and resolve advanced problems.
- Monitored systems in operation and quickly troubleshot errors.
- Used ticketing systems to manage and process support actions and requests.

EDUCATION

2023

Software Engineer certifications Zero To Mastery Academy, Denton, TX

2013

Bachelors: Information Technology University of Phoenix, Waldron, AR Associate: Fine Arts - Digital Graphic arts

Remington College, Fort Worth, TX

Willing to relocate to

CERTIFICATIONS

- Leadership Foundations Training November 2022 to Present
- Instructional Design for ELearning Training December 2022 to Present
- ADDIE Training January 2023 to present
- Adobe Captivate Training January 2023 to present